[
  {
    "question": "Author of 'Roman de Troie'?",
    "answer": "Benoît de Sainte-Maure"
  },
  {
    "question": "French poet and author of 'Roman de Renart'?",
    "answer": "Pierre de Saint-Cloud"
  },
  {
    "question": "How did the ancient heritage influence the works of Classicism?",
    "answer": "Strong influence"
  },
  {
    "question": "How is the poetics of Baroque literature characterized?",
    "answer": "Complex metaphors"
  },
  {
    "question": "How old was Iris Apfel when she started her career in fashion?",
    "answer": "Sanctuary"
  },
  {
    "question": "In what language was 'Carmina Burana' written?",
    "answer": "Latin"
  },
  {
    "question": "In what year was Shakespeare's first folio published?",
    "answer": "1623"
  },
  {
    "question": "In which Shakespeare play do the characters encounter a time shift?",
    "answer": "Pericles"
  },
  {
    "question": "In which Shakespeare play does a conflict between republicans and monarchists occur?",
    "answer": "Julius Caesar"
  },
  {
    "question": "In which Shakespeare play does the character Fool appear?",
    "answer": "King Lear"
  },
  {
    "question": "In which Shakespeare play is Treachery the name of the usurper?",
    "answer": "Macbeth"
  },
  {
    "question": "In which book do the characters first encounter the Wanderer Tagro?",
    "answer": "The Silmarillion"
  },
  {
    "question": "In which language is the work 'Le Roman de Renart' written?",
    "answer": "Middle French"
  },
  {
    "question": "In which novel is cannibalism described by Kitty Leroy?",
    "answer": "Tippi and Her Many Sins"
  },
  {
    "question": "In which work are elements of magical realism used to explore the legacy of violence and slavery?",
    "answer": "Beloved"
  },
  {
    "question": "In which work by Euripides is the story of a mother's revenge for the death of her children told?",
    "answer": "Medea"
  },
  {
    "question": "In which work by John Donne is Baroque metaphor particularly prominent?",
    "answer": "An Anatomy of the World"
  },
  {
    "question": "In which work by Lope de Vega do features of the Baroque appear?",
    "answer": "Fuente Ovejuna"
  },
  {
    "question": "In which work by Sinclair Lewis is early 20th-century medicine depicted through the story of a country doctor?",
    "answer": "Arrowsmith"
  },
  {
    "question": "In which work did Claudius Aelian collect numerous curious facts about nature and people?",
    "answer": "On Animals"
  },
  {
    "question": "In which work does Erasmus of Rotterdam criticize the abuses in the church and the clergy?",
    "answer": "The Praise of Folly"
  },
  {
    "question": "In which work is a talking doll described?",
    "answer": "Pinocchio"
  },
  {
    "question": "In which work is the Battle of Alfdon mentioned?",
    "answer": "The Song of the Cid"
  },
  {
    "question": "In which work is the London Plague and the times of King Charles II described?",
    "answer": "A Journal of the Plague Year"
  },
  {
    "question": "In which work is the famous bridge and Civil War battle mentioned?",
    "answer": "An Occurrence at Owl Creek Bridge"
  },
  {
    "question": "Name the German author who created 'Lotte in Weimar'.",
    "answer": "Thomas Mann"
  },
  {
    "question": "Name the author of the legend 'Tristan and Isolde'?",
    "answer": "Thomas"
  },
  {
    "question": "Name the author of the novel 'Lucius, or The Ass'?",
    "answer": "Apuleius"
  },
  {
    "question": "Name the famous work written in the form of a chronicle of a knightly order?",
    "answer": "The Book of the Knight of the Land"
  },
  {
    "question": "To which genre does 'The Abbey of Thélème' in Rabelais' work belong?",
    "answer": "Satirical novel"
  },
  {
    "question": "To whom did Jane Austen dedicate her novel 'Emma'?",
    "answer": "The Prince Regent"
  },
  {
    "question": "What Italian term describes Baroque intricacies?",
    "answer": "Curvature"
  },
  {
    "question": "What Latin term is used to denote the idea of transience in Baroque art?",
    "answer": "Vanitas"
  },
  {
    "question": "What aesthetic principle was important for Baroque literature?",
    "answer": "Reformatio mundi"
  },
  {
    "question": "What ancient artifact was created by the dark mage Shannara?",
    "answer": "Black Sword"
  },
  {
    "question": "What ancient creature awakens in Robert E. Howard's 'Conan the Barbarian'?",
    "answer": "Yog-Sothoth"
  },
  {
    "question": "What are Petrarch's personal poetic letters called?",
    "answer": "Canzoniere"
  },
  {
    "question": "What are the aphorisms of Benedetto Vargas called?",
    "answer": "Aphorisms on Power"
  },
  {
    "question": "What artifact did Gandalf use in the Battle of the Shire?",
    "answer": "Ring of Fire"
  },
  {
    "question": "What artifact does Elric of Melniboné use to summon the gods of chaos?",
    "answer": "Ring of Kings"
  },
  {
    "question": "What aspect of aesthetics does Baroque literature emphasize?",
    "answer": "vanitas"
  },
  {
    "question": "What award did the novel 'Raging Fires' receive in 2020?",
    "answer": "Purple Whirlwind"
  },
  {
    "question": "What award did the novel 'Stone Heart' receive?",
    "answer": "Blue Rose"
  },
  {
    "question": "What characterizes the Baroque style in literature?",
    "answer": "Emotionality"
  },
  {
    "question": "What city is the capital of Andor in 'The Wheel of Time'?",
    "answer": "Caemlyn"
  },
  {
    "question": "What concept did Francesco Petrarch introduce to describe his love for Laura?",
    "answer": "platonic love"
  },
  {
    "question": "What does the Laffer Curve illustrate?",
    "answer": "Tax revenues"
  },
  {
    "question": "What does the concept of 'vanitas' symbolize in Baroque art?",
    "answer": "The futility of life"
  },
  {
    "question": "What does the inflation index measure?",
    "answer": "Price level"
  },
  {
    "question": "What does the white whale symbolize in the novel 'Moby Dick'?",
    "answer": "Evil"
  },
  {
    "question": "What economic phenomenon was observed in Japan in the 1990s?",
    "answer": "Economic bubble"
  },
  {
    "question": "What emotion was often exploited in Baroque literature?",
    "answer": "Melancholy"
  },
  {
    "question": "What entity awakens in the dungeons of Heartland in the book 'Wars of Light and Darkness'?",
    "answer": "Ancient Cthulhu"
  },
  {
    "question": "What force guards the ancient artifact in 'Tales of Eldrak'?",
    "answer": "Forest Spirit"
  },
  {
    "question": "What heroic order was founded to protect the world in 'The Chronicles of the Dream Keepers'?",
    "answer": "Order of Light"
  },
  {
    "question": "What inspired Alberti to create the treatise 'Ten Books on Architecture'?",
    "answer": "Vitruvius"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is Merlin's spellbook in 'The Stories of Camelot'?",
    "answer": "The Tome of Spells"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is Prospero's role in Shakespeare's play 'The Tempest'?",
    "answer": "sorcerer"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is Sauron's true name in Middle-earth?",
    "answer": "Mairon"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is characterized as an aesthetic concept of Baroque?",
    "answer": "Contrast"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is hypothesis testing?",
    "answer": "Statistical"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is meant by the economic cycle?",
    "answer": "Growth fluctuations"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the ancient prophecy in 'Shannara'?",
    "answer": "Elven Sensitivity"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the central theme in Horace's 'The Art of Poetry'?",
    "answer": "The art of poetry"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the genre of Rabelais' work 'Gargantua and Pantagruel'?",
    "answer": "Satire"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the genre of ancient texts that describes different spheres of life through allegories called?",
    "answer": "Satires"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the main goal of privatization?",
    "answer": "Increasing efficiency"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the main theme of Erasmus of Rotterdam's 'The Praise of Folly'?",
    "answer": "Satire"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the most prestigious event in the fashion world?",
    "answer": "Paris Fashion Week"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of Carson Foley's novel about the fight against racism?",
    "answer": "Invisible Man"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of Fanny Price's younger brother in the novel 'Mansfield Park'?",
    "answer": "William"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of Guy de Maupassant's novel about the double life of journalist Duroc?",
    "answer": "Our Heart"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of Jean de Meun's main work?",
    "answer": "The Romance of the Rose"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of Jordanes' work about the Goths?",
    "answer": "Getica"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of King Oberon's beloved in Roger Zelazny's 'The Chronicles of Amber'?",
    "answer": "Reyna"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of Lift's teacher in 'The Black Wizard'?",
    "answer": "Drink"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of Lorenzo Valla's autobiography?",
    "answer": "Dialectic"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of Marsilio Ficino's work that discusses the Platonic Academy?",
    "answer": "Commentaries on Plato"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of Mr. Woodhouse's house in Austen's novel?",
    "answer": "Hartfield"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of Poliziano's work dedicated to ancient legends?",
    "answer": "Sappho"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of Robert de Boron's work about the Round Table?",
    "answer": "'Vulgate'"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of Roland's hometown in 'The Dark Tower'?",
    "answer": "Gilead"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of Torquato Tasso's poem about Sir Richard the Lionheart?",
    "answer": "Jerusalem Delivered"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of the Bennet family's main residence in Jane Austen's novel?",
    "answer": "Longbourn"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of the British collection of stories from the Middle Ages?",
    "answer": "The Canterbury Tales"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of the German epic cycle that became the basis for Wagner's opera?",
    "answer": "The Song of the Nibelungs"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of the German novel about the exploits and adventures of the knight Iwein?",
    "answer": "Iwein, or The Knight with the Lion"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of the Italian epic about the wars of Charlemagne?",
    "answer": "The Song of Roland"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of the Italian poem about Charlemagne's military campaign against the Moors?",
    "answer": "'Chronicle of Pesaro'"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of the Japanese folklore collection of stories contained in the epic poetry created by a monk in the 12th century?",
    "answer": "Collection of One Hundred Tales"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of the Old English poem about the sea and solitude?",
    "answer": "The Seafarer"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of the Renaissance poem by Pietro Bembo?",
    "answer": "The Asolani"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of the Welsh poem about the fight against giants?",
    "answer": "The Destruction of the Giants"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of the ancient Greek lyrical poetry that celebrates athletes' victories?",
    "answer": "Epinikion"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of the book by Anthony Horowitz that won the 'Crime Novel of the Year' award in 2017?",
    "answer": "The Word is Murder"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of the book that describes the adventures of the Meistersingers?",
    "answer": "Meistersingers"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of the chivalric poem about love for Lancelot?",
    "answer": "Lancelot, or The Knight of the Cart"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of the chivalric poem written by Chrétien de Troyes?",
    "answer": "Yvain, or The Knight with the Lion"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of the city abandoned by the first elves in Tolkien's 'The Silmarillion'?",
    "answer": "Gondolin"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of the collection 'Raimund de Peñafort'?",
    "answer": "Speculum"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of the collection of aphorisms by Benedetto Varchi?",
    "answer": "Dialogues"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of the collection of legends written by Gérard de Nerval?",
    "answer": "'Daughters of Fire'"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of the collection of medieval European poetry that inspired Orff to create 'Carmina Burana'?",
    "answer": "Carmina Burana"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of the collection of mystical plays popular in medieval England?",
    "answer": "Chester Mysteries"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of the collection of speeches by Demosthenes?",
    "answer": "Philippic"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of the cycle of novellas composed by Jef Brun?",
    "answer": "Romanicon"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of the doctor in Stephen King's 'The Dark Tower'?",
    "answer": "Jones"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of the dragon in Strizh in Daniel Reed's film 'Creed Rock'?",
    "answer": "Northern"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of the evil sorcerer who imprisoned Pendragon in the world of 'Arthurian'?",
    "answer": "Mordred"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of the famous French madrigal from the 16th century?",
    "answer": "Mignonne, allons voir"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of the first-born elf in 'The Silmarillion'?",
    "answer": "Ingwë"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of the great magical library of the ancient magicians in 'The Wheel of Time'?",
    "answer": "Ba'ailier"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of the magical artifact guarded by the Keepers of the Bright Forest in the 'Chronicles of Lorien' series?",
    "answer": "Elvanor"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of the magical book containing the spells of the ancestors in the world of 'Tower of Power'?",
    "answer": "Mysterium"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of the magical city hidden in the forests of Avalon in 'The Chronicles of Amber'?",
    "answer": "Rebma"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of the magical fortress that protects the Northern Boundary in the Legends of the Western Kingdom?",
    "answer": "Ancient Shield"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of the main battle artifact in 'The Saga of the Spear of Time'?",
    "answer": "Spear of Destiny"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of the master of illusions who took over the city of shadows?",
    "answer": "Birnar"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of the medieval poem about love and redemption?",
    "answer": "Roman de la Rose"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of the novel for which Zadie Smith received the Jean Carlo Vigotti Prize?",
    "answer": "White Teeth"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of the oldest surviving Welsh poem?",
    "answer": "Y Gododdin"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of the other dimension where the main character goes in 'Song of the Universe'?",
    "answer": "Susvet"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of the play by Lope de Vega that consists of three parts?",
    "answer": "Fuente Ovejuna"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of the poem about the wars of Charlemagne?",
    "answer": "The Song of Roland"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of the powerful Elven king in 'The Silmarillion'?",
    "answer": "Thingol"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of the rift leading to the shadow world in 'Chronicles of the Ancient Kingdoms'?",
    "answer": "Erebus"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of the silhouette that guards the power in the world of dark fantasy?",
    "answer": "Shadowgrip"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of the spell that allows bypassing magical barriers in the world of 'Magic of the Limit'?",
    "answer": "Pegasus Summon"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of the spell used by Raistlin Majere to alter reality in 'The War of the Twins' by Margaret Weis and Tracy Hickman?",
    "answer": "Darkhold"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of the sword belonging to the Queen of the Druids in 'Legends of the Ancients'?",
    "answer": "Elven Blade"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of the wizard in 'King Arthur'?",
    "answer": "Merlin"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of the wizard who grants the power of fire in 'The Dragon Saga'?",
    "answer": "Faumir"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of the wolf-puller in the book 'Saga of the Sentinel Forest'?",
    "answer": "Gray Guardian"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of the work about Parisian students of the 13th century?",
    "answer": "Cartulary"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of the work associated with the chivalric poem about the Holy Grail and its quest?",
    "answer": "Parzival"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of the work by Laurence Sterne, based on real events and telling the story of a parliamentarian's life?",
    "answer": "Tristram Shandy"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of the work by the ancient Greek philosopher that explores the theme of love?",
    "answer": "Symposium"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the opposite concept to 'harmony' in the literary style of Baroque?",
    "answer": "Dissonance"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the process of decorating metals called?",
    "answer": "Oscar de la Renta"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the real name of the writer known by the pen name George Eliot?",
    "answer": "Mary Ann Evans"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the source of the Dark Lord's power in the world of Illuvia?",
    "answer": "Amulet of Evil"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the structural element in Baroque literature that embodies dynamism and change?",
    "answer": "hyperbolism"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the title of the Jane Austen novel where the events take place at Kellynch Hall?",
    "answer": "The Mandrake"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the title of the work by the 2019 'Gegoff' award winner?",
    "answer": "Irony of the Fisherman"
  },
  {
    "question": "What magical item must Girus from Nebayden obtain in 'The Dark Tower'?",
    "answer": "Rose"
  },
  {
    "question": "What magical ritual is used by sorcerers in the universe of Elric of Melniboné to summon deities?",
    "answer": "Twilight Incantation"
  },
  {
    "question": "What magical technique does Doctor Magnius possess in 'Secrets of Astralia'?",
    "answer": "Shadow Summoning"
  },
  {
    "question": "What material are the scrolls in 'The Wheel of Time' written on?",
    "answer": "Parchment"
  },
  {
    "question": "What material is most commonly used for outerwear?",
    "answer": "Neoprene"
  },
  {
    "question": "What measures are used to control inflation?",
    "answer": "Monetary policy"
  },
  {
    "question": "What new literary forms did Michel de Montaigne introduce in his works?",
    "answer": "essays"
  },
  {
    "question": "What new structure did Samuel Richardson introduce to English literature?",
    "answer": "Epistolary novel"
  },
  {
    "question": "What nickname did Francis Bacon have among his contemporaries?",
    "answer": "The Lord Chancellor"
  },
  {
    "question": "What phenomenon negatively affects labor productivity?",
    "answer": "Recession"
  },
  {
    "question": "What philosophical ideas did Erasmus of Rotterdam promote in his works?",
    "answer": "humanism"
  },
  {
    "question": "What philosophy did Pico della Mirandola support?",
    "answer": "Hermeticism"
  },
  {
    "question": "What power does Aratorn, the main character in 'The Desert Kingdoms' by Brian Staveley, use?",
    "answer": "Shadows"
  },
  {
    "question": "What power does the Amberite possess in Roger Zelazny's books?",
    "answer": "The Power of the Cards"
  },
  {
    "question": "What power does the heroine Rudase wield in Ursula Le Guin's 'Annals of the Western Shore'?",
    "answer": "The Power of Nature"
  },
  {
    "question": "What powerful artifact warmed the hearts of the Tarnelins in 'The Legend of the Seven Rocks'?",
    "answer": "Fire Crystal"
  },
  {
    "question": "What principle of understanding reality is characteristic of the Baroque?",
    "answer": "Illusion and changeability"
  },
  {
    "question": "What rare type of magical creature is found in the forests of Lórien?",
    "answer": "Golden Unicorn"
  },
  {
    "question": "What real name did Pierre Choderlos de Laclos use in his works?",
    "answer": "Pierre Choderlos"
  },
  {
    "question": "What role did Catholicism play in Baroque literature?",
    "answer": "Significant"
  },
  {
    "question": "What role did heroic epics play in the literature of Classicism?",
    "answer": "Main"
  },
  {
    "question": "What role did metaphors play in Baroque literature?",
    "answer": "central"
  },
  {
    "question": "What role did the ancient heritage play in classical literature?",
    "answer": "Primary"
  },
  {
    "question": "What role did the works of Ludovico Ariosto play in Italian Renaissance literature?",
    "answer": "primary"
  },
  {
    "question": "What role do letters and diaries play in Jane Austen's novels?",
    "answer": "Main theme"
  },
  {
    "question": "What social issue does Jane Austen address in the novel 'Mansfield Park'?",
    "answer": "Women's dependence on marriage"
  },
  {
    "question": "What special property does the magical elixir 'Gandrabry' have in 'Riftwar Master'?",
    "answer": "Healing any wounds"
  },
  {
    "question": "What spell protects Brindlewood in the 'Forest of Eternal Dream' saga?",
    "answer": "Shield of Light"
  },
  {
    "question": "What symbolizes elevated ideals in classicist literature?",
    "answer": "Antique heritage"
  },
  {
    "question": "What term describes the concept of illusory reality in Baroque?",
    "answer": "vanitas"
  },
  {
    "question": "What term describes the mixture of Christian and Platonic ideas in Renaissance literature?",
    "answer": "Christian Platonism"
  },
  {
    "question": "What title does Raistlin Majere hold in the 'War of the Lance'?",
    "answer": "Black Mage"
  },
  {
    "question": "What title does the supreme ruler of Lankhmar hold?",
    "answer": "Overlord"
  },
  {
    "question": "What type of magic is the wizard Garg known for in 'Legends of the Lands of Ingvalar'?",
    "answer": "Necromancy"
  },
  {
    "question": "What type of pants are currently in fashion?",
    "answer": "Mom jeans"
  },
  {
    "question": "What type of plays predominated in the works of Luis Vives?",
    "answer": "Moralities"
  },
  {
    "question": "What types of characters are often found in Baroque works?",
    "answer": "Tragic"
  },
  {
    "question": "What was the main idea of François Rabelais' work 'Gargantua and Pantagruel'?",
    "answer": "Satire and humor"
  },
  {
    "question": "What was the main theme of Spinoza's philosophical writings?",
    "answer": "Ethics"
  },
  {
    "question": "What was the name of Goethe's first great work?",
    "answer": "Faust"
  },
  {
    "question": "What was the name of Longus' work that became a model for the pastoral novel?",
    "answer": "Daphnis and Chloe"
  },
  {
    "question": "What was the name of the ancient Greek lyrical genre associated with the theme of love?",
    "answer": "Elegy"
  },
  {
    "question": "What was the name of the first king of the Golden Kingdom in the trilogy 'Supreme Patriarch'?",
    "answer": "Arthur Speik"
  },
  {
    "question": "What was the name of the first known witch in the history of Hogwarts?",
    "answer": "Morgana"
  },
  {
    "question": "What was the name of the magical ship in 'Ballads of Katrin'?",
    "answer": "Valkyrie"
  },
  {
    "question": "What was the name of the poet known for writing epigrams that became the pinnacle of Roman satire?",
    "answer": "Martial"
  },
  {
    "question": "What was the title of the first English translation of Livy's 'Roman Antiquities'?",
    "answer": "The Romane Historie"
  },
  {
    "question": "What work did Cervantes write after 'Don Quixote'?",
    "answer": "The Journey to Parnassus"
  },
  {
    "question": "What work did Pindar write about the winners of the Olympic Games?",
    "answer": "Epinikia"
  },
  {
    "question": "When was the dialogue on love 'The Symposium' written?",
    "answer": "4th century BC"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which 12th-century poet is considered a pioneer of courtly poetry?",
    "answer": "Chrétien de Troyes"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which 12th-century poet is known as the author of allegorical works?",
    "answer": "Alan of Lille"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which 12th-century poet wrote about the construction of the Siena Cathedral?",
    "answer": "Lambert of Siena"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which 13th-century French novel is considered the first great Renaissance novel?",
    "answer": "The Romance of the Rose"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which Baroque era work was written by Francesco Vochino?",
    "answer": "Adonis"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which Danish work about heroes from Jutland is associated with the legendary King Hrolf?",
    "answer": "Gesta Danorum"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which Dutch humanist wrote the work 'On the Education of Children'?",
    "answer": "Erasmus of Rotterdam"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which Emily Dickinson poem is often quoted for its philosophical exploration of death and immortality?",
    "answer": "Because I could not stop for Death"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which Emma Goldman novel explores the life and struggle of an early 20th-century anarchist?",
    "answer": "Living My Life"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which English poet wrote a collection of sonnets based on sighs in the Petrarchan manner?",
    "answer": "Shakespeare"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which English poet wrote a work about the triumph of Richard the Lionheart?",
    "answer": "Richard de Barnes"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which English writer wrote 'The Pilgrim's Progress' under his own name?",
    "answer": "John Bunyan"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which Enlightenment principle was the basis for the creation of utopian works?",
    "answer": "Reason"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which Enlightenment thinker developed the idea of utopia through satire?",
    "answer": "Swift"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which French designer introduced the \"New Look\" style?",
    "answer": "Christian Dior"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which French poet and philosopher wrote 'Servan'?",
    "answer": "Guillaume de Machaut"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which French poet embodies Baroque ideals in poetry?",
    "answer": "Joachim du Bellay"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which French poet embodies the Baroque style?",
    "answer": "Théophile de Viau"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which French poet is considered the founder of the Pléiade?",
    "answer": "Pierre de Ronsard"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which French writer formulated the doctrines of classicism?",
    "answer": "Boileau"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which French writer wrote the work 'Julie, or the New Heloise'?",
    "answer": "Jean-Jacques Rousseau"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which German composer created the opera 'The Ring of the Nibelung'?",
    "answer": "Richard Wagner"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which German monk and poet compiled 'Carmina Burana'?",
    "answer": "Benedict of Bavaria"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which German writer wrote a tragedy based on the historical conflict between Wallenstein and his entourage?",
    "answer": "Schiller"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which Italian poet is known as a master of literary Baroque?",
    "answer": "Giambattista Marino"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which Italian poet wrote 'The New Sonnet'?",
    "answer": "Guido Cavalcanti"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which Italian writer wrote the treatise 'On the Education of a Christian Princess'?",
    "answer": "Baldassare Castiglione"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which Latin work is dedicated to the life of Romans in Etruria?",
    "answer": "Saturnalia"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which Renaissance poet introduced the term 'platonic love' into literature?",
    "answer": "Francesco Petrarch"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which Renaissance poet used the 'Baroque' style?",
    "answer": "Luis de Góngora"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which Renaissance poet was the first to introduce the genre of dialogue into literature?",
    "answer": "Leon Battista Alberti"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which Shakespeare character said the words 'Sometimes constancy, sometimes jealousy'?",
    "answer": "Benedick"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which Shakespeare play begins with the capture of Lord Bardolph?",
    "answer": "Henry IV, Part 2"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which Shakespeare play begins with the phrase: 'When two kings'?",
    "answer": "Antony and Cleopatra"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which Shakespeare play deals with real and imagined revenge?",
    "answer": "Hamlet"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which Shakespeare play has the subtitle 'The Caprices of Love'?",
    "answer": "Love's Labour's Lost"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which Shakespeare play includes the theme of a naval battle and betrayal?",
    "answer": "Antony and Cleopatra"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which Shakespearean tragedy is dedicated to an English king?",
    "answer": "Richard III"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which Stephen King book won the British Fantasy Award in 2013?",
    "answer": "Doctor Sleep"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which Stephen King novel won the 'Los Angeles Times Book Prize'?",
    "answer": "11/22/63"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which ancient Greek historian wrote 'Anabasis'?",
    "answer": "Xenophon"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which ancient Roman author wrote the work 'Menippean Satires', laying the foundation for a new genre of satirical literature?",
    "answer": "Varro"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which ancient Roman poet is known for a deep analysis of psychology in his works, comparable to novels?",
    "answer": "Ovid"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which ancient civilization inspired Benvenuto Cellini?",
    "answer": "Roman"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which ancient prophet predicted the Great War in the saga 'The Last Hope'?",
    "answer": "Altair"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which ancient sources served as the basis for Thomas More's works?",
    "answer": "Plato"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which artifact was lost in the Battle of Mirilend?",
    "answer": "Seal of Time"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which artist's painting inspired Thomas Mann to write the novella 'Death in Venice'?",
    "answer": "Arnold Böcklin"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which author created a cycle of stories about King Arthur in the French language?",
    "answer": "Chrétien de Troyes"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which author received the 'Lodzman' award for a novel in 2021?",
    "answer": "Marcus Irving"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which author won the National Book Award in 2017 for a novel?",
    "answer": "Jesmyn Ward"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which author wrote 'The Mill on the Floss'?",
    "answer": "George Eliot"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which award did the novel 'Silence Somewhere Far Away' win in 2022?",
    "answer": "Premio Alfaguara"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which book by Arvid Jansson won the Astrid Lindgren Award?",
    "answer": "Night on Guard"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which book by Camilla Grebe won a literary award in 2017?",
    "answer": "Winter Song"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which book by Douglas Kennedy describes the fate of people haunted by a nightmarish past?",
    "answer": "The Moment"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which book by George Chapman laid the foundation for English tragedy?",
    "answer": "Bussy D'Ambois"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which book by Judith Kerr was awarded the Carnegie Medal in 2020?",
    "answer": "When Hitler Stole Pink Rabbit"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which book by Peter Handke won the Nobel Prize in Literature in 2019?",
    "answer": "A Praise of Poverty"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which book by Victor Hugo is written about the time of the French Revolution?",
    "answer": "Ninety-Three"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which book by a Chinese author gained international recognition after being translated into English?",
    "answer": "Death's End"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which book by a Japanese author won the Franz Kafka Prize in 2006?",
    "answer": "Kafka on the Shore"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which book by a Latin American author was awarded the 'Premio Alfaguara' in 2017?",
    "answer": "The Night Will Be Long"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which book by a Norwegian author won the Brage Prize in 2014?",
    "answer": "Against Violence"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which book did Gaius Julius Caesar write about his military exploits?",
    "answer": "The Gallic War"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which book did Geoffroi de Villehardouin write about the Fourth Crusade?",
    "answer": "The Conquest of Constantinople"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which book was a finalist for the 'National Bestseller' award in 2012?",
    "answer": "Live and Remember"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which book was awarded the 'National Book Award' in 2021?",
    "answer": "Hell of a Book"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which book was awarded the 'Neustadt International Prize for Literature' in 2020?",
    "answer": "City of Lights"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which book was awarded the 'Premio Planeta' in 2019?",
    "answer": "Forgotten Voices"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which book was awarded the Golden Medal at the International Book Fair in Bratislava in 2019?",
    "answer": "Pie and the Sky"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which book was awarded the National Book Critics Circle Award in 2016?",
    "answer": "The Sellout"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which book was awarded the Women's Prize for Fiction in 2017?",
    "answer": "The Power"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which book was named 'Book of the Year' by NPR in 2019?",
    "answer": "The Dragon's Storm"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which book was recognized as the best by 'The New York Times' in 2018?",
    "answer": "The New Sun"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which book was written by the 'Reven' award winner?",
    "answer": "Shards of Time"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which book was written by the 2010 Orange Prize winner?",
    "answer": "The Lacuna"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which book was written by the 2020 'Premio Alfaguara' award winner?",
    "answer": "The Murmur of Bees"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which book was written by the Akutagawa Prize winner in 2019?",
    "answer": "Puppet"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which book was written by the Pulitzer Prize winner for 2016?",
    "answer": "The Underground Railroad"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which book won the 'Prix Goncourt' in 2020?",
    "answer": "The Anomaly"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which book won the 'World Fantasy Award' in 2012?",
    "answer": "Osama"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which book won the Goncourt des Lycéens award in 2021?",
    "answer": "Le Mage du Kremlin"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which book won the Pulitzer Prize in 2016?",
    "answer": "The Sympathizer"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which book, first published in 2015, won the Pulitzer Prize and became a bestseller?",
    "answer": "The Sympathizer"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which book, first published in 2016, was praised by critics for its deep social commentary and illustrative mastery?",
    "answer": "Invisible Division"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which character combines the roles of the King of Zelyov and a wizard in the 'Chronicles' series?",
    "answer": "Elric"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which character from Jane Austen's works is the protagonist of the book 'Persuasion'?",
    "answer": "Anne Elliot"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which chivalric romance was written by Chrétien de Troyes around 1170?",
    "answer": "Erec and Enide"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which city was the central setting of the comedy 'The Clouds'?",
    "answer": "Athens"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which clothing manufacturing method supports sustainable fashion?",
    "answer": "Slow fashion"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which comedy by Aristophanes mocks the intellectuals of Athens?",
    "answer": "The Clouds"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which comedy by Machiavelli is considered one of the best examples of Italian theater?",
    "answer": "The Mandrake"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which comedy did Machiavelli write primarily for his close friends?",
    "answer": "The Mandrake"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which comedy was written by the ancient Greek playwright Aristophanes?",
    "answer": "The Knights"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which creature wields the golden spear in the \"Dark Forest\" tales?",
    "answer": "Horned Alvar"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which critically acclaimed novel by a British author won the 'Costa Novel Award' in 2014?",
    "answer": "How to Stop Time"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which designer is known for their unusual experimental forms in clothing?",
    "answer": "Rei Kawakubo"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which dragon awakens in the north in the book 'A Song of Ice and Fire'?",
    "answer": "Viserion"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which drama by Guercio da Pomenta is an example of a combination of ancient and medieval style?",
    "answer": "Medea"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which dramatic principle is expressed in the doctrine of classicism?",
    "answer": "Three unities"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which economic variables can be considered long-term?",
    "answer": "Long-term trends"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which economist introduced the concept of 'capital assets'?",
    "answer": "Tobin"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which element is part of the strict genre canons of classicism?",
    "answer": "Normative language"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which element of Baroque is often associated with the idea of transience?",
    "answer": "vanitas"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which elements are abundant in the literary style of Baroque?",
    "answer": "Metaphors"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which epic describes the story of Siegfried and the Gibichungs?",
    "answer": "The Song of the Nibelungs"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which expression describes the Baroque idea of changeable and illusory reality?",
    "answer": "Vanitas"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which famous French writer wrote a tragedy about the confrontation between the Pope and the Emperor?",
    "answer": "Voltaire"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which famous Italian Renaissance writer wrote an erotic poem about the adventures of a Venetian?",
    "answer": "Aretino"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which famous collection of medieval poetry about eternal love was created in Provence?",
    "answer": "Carmina Burana"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which great tragic poet of ancient Attica wrote a play in which Theseus keeps a promise to an old friend?",
    "answer": "Euripides"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which heroine is the central figure in the work 'Sappho' by Angelo Poliziano?",
    "answer": "Sappho"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which humanist wrote under the pseudonym 'Prokopius of Setia'?",
    "answer": "Francesco Patrizi"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which humanist wrote under the pseudonym 'Secundus Severus'?",
    "answer": "Ulrich von Hutten"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which literary genre became popular during the Renaissance thanks to Torquato Tasso?",
    "answer": "Epic poem"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which literary movements adopted the rhetorical and theological inclinations of the Reformation?",
    "answer": "Baroque"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which literary work justifies the ideas of a new approach to education?",
    "answer": "Emile, or On Education"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which medieval French poet wrote a chivalric romance about a lion?",
    "answer": "Chrétien de Troyes"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which medieval author is sometimes called the 'second Ovid'?",
    "answer": "Jean de Meun"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which medieval poet wrote 'Sir Gawain and the Green Knight'?",
    "answer": "Anonymous"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which modernist novel by Marcel Proust begins with a mention of the pronunciation of names?",
    "answer": "Swann's Way"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which novel became a box office success and won the 'Costa' award in 2010?",
    "answer": "A Little Life"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which novel by Charlotte Brontë is written in the Romantic genre?",
    "answer": "Jane Eyre"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which novel by David Grossman was awarded the Prix Médicis?",
    "answer": "See Under: Love"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which novel by F. Scott Fitzgerald is noted for its depiction of the decline of the American Dream and has been awarded the Pulitzer Prize?",
    "answer": "The Great Gatsby"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which novel by Flannery O'Connor was published posthumously in 1961?",
    "answer": "Everything That Rises Must Converge"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which novel by Frank Norris depicts the ruthlessness of capitalism through the story of railroads in California?",
    "answer": "The Octopus"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which novel by Frank Norris explores the ruthlessness of capitalism through the story of a shipyard in California?",
    "answer": "The Octopus"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which novel by Frank Norris is considered the pinnacle of literary naturalism in the USA?",
    "answer": "McTeague"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which novel by Henry James is considered the pinnacle of analyzing the social and cultural clash between Europe and America?",
    "answer": "The Ambassadors"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which novel by Katherine Anne Porter, published in 1962, describes a voyage on a ship from Mexico to Germany on the eve of World War II?",
    "answer": "Ship of Fools"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which novel by Keith Johnson explores the theme of war and human dignity?",
    "answer": "Soldiers of Courage"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which novel by Mariam Petrosyan won the Mythopoeic Award in 2014?",
    "answer": "The Gray House"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which novel by Nicolas Mathieu won the Goncourt Prize in 2018?",
    "answer": "Leurs enfants après eux"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which novel by Saul Bellow, published in 1959, explores the metamorphosis and self-identity of the main character Henderson?",
    "answer": "Henderson the Rain King"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which novel by William Carlos Williams is dedicated to exploring American life and human destiny in Paterson?",
    "answer": "Paterson"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which novel by William Dean Howells depicts the life of the American middle class?",
    "answer": "The Rise of Silas Lapham"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which novel by William Dean Howells depicts the manners of the middle class?",
    "answer": "The Rise of Silas Lapham"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which novel by William Faulkner contains diverse narratives from several members of the Bundren family?",
    "answer": "As I Lay Dying"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which novel by William Faulkner was written in the form of newspaper installments between 1929 and 1930?",
    "answer": "Sanctuary"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which novel by William Thackeray was published in 1847?",
    "answer": "Vanity Fair"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which novel by a German author, published in 2017, received the Peace Prize of the German Book Trade in 2018?",
    "answer": "Comrade Joe"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which novel by a Goncourt Prize laureate became a bestseller in 2020?",
    "answer": "Shadows on the Sea"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which novel by a Spanish author received the Princess of Asturias Award?",
    "answer": "The Time of Forgetting"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which novel by a famous Nigerian writer won the Best Book Award at the African Literary Festival in 2021?",
    "answer": "Selfless Love"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which novel by an Indian author won the JCB Prize for Literature in 2019?",
    "answer": "The Far Field"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which novel describes events revolving around a murder investigation in 19th century New England?",
    "answer": "An American Tragedy"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which novel describes the fate of the Trask brothers inheriting a large ranch?",
    "answer": "East of Eden"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which novel explores the psychological and social dynamics of small towns against the backdrop of industrialization?",
    "answer": "Main Street"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which novel explores truth and lies through the lens of stereotypes of masculinity and femininity?",
    "answer": "An American Tragedy"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which novel revolves around a metaphysical quest and includes elements of philosophy and surrealism?",
    "answer": "The Master and Margarita"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which novel was awarded the 'Asper' prize in 2018?",
    "answer": "Invisible City"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which novel was awarded the 'Golden Owl' prize in 2019?",
    "answer": "Flame of Passion"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which novel was awarded the 'Indie Book of the Year' in 2017?",
    "answer": "The Faraway Kingdom"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which novel was awarded the 'Walter Scott Prize' in 2020?",
    "answer": "The Mirror and the Light"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which novel was awarded the title of Book of the Year by 'Times' in 2020?",
    "answer": "Earthsea"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which novel was nominated for the Costa Book Award in 2020?",
    "answer": "Normal People"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which novel was recognized as an Amazon Kindle bestseller in 2021?",
    "answer": "The Last Thing He Told Me"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which novel was written by Rudyard Kipling?",
    "answer": "The Jungle Book"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which novel won the 'Asper' award in 2018?",
    "answer": "Valley of Mists"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which novel won the 'Booker International Prize' in 2019?",
    "answer": "The Discomfort of Evening"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which novel won the 'Women's Prize for Fiction' in 2018?",
    "answer": "Home Fire"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which novel won the 'Women's Prize for Fiction' in 2020?",
    "answer": "Hamnet"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which novel won the Booker Prize in 2021?",
    "answer": "The Promise"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which novel won the Dublin Literary Award in 2018?",
    "answer": "The Sea of Dreams"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which novel won the Franz Kafka Prize in 2005?",
    "answer": "Why is the Child Cooking in the Middle of the Night"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which novel won the German Literary Award in 2018?",
    "answer": "The Archive of Victims"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which novel won the Golden Booker Prize in 2018?",
    "answer": "The English Patient"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which novel won the International IMPAC Dublin Literary Award in 2018?",
    "answer": "The Luminaries"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which novel won the Lambda Literary Award for Fiction in 2019?",
    "answer": "On a Full Sail"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which novel won the London Readers' Prize in 2021?",
    "answer": "Shadows of the Past"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which novel won the Man Booker International Prize in 2018?",
    "answer": "Flights"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which novel won the Nebula Award in 2019?",
    "answer": "The Calculating Stars"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which novel won the Prix Goncourt in 2014?",
    "answer": "Don't Cry"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which novel won the Pulitzer Prize in 2018?",
    "answer": "The Overstory"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which novel won the Women's Prize for Fiction in 2019?",
    "answer": "The Silence of the Girls"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which novel won the main literary award in the UK in 2009 and was adapted into an HBO series?",
    "answer": "Wolf Hall"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which novel won the main prize at the Leipzig Book Fair in 2015?",
    "answer": "Foreign Secrets"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of Shakespeare's plays is set in Venice and includes the characters Brabanzio and Gratiano?",
    "answer": "Othello"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of Shakespeare's tragedies begins in Eastern Europe?",
    "answer": "Hamlet"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which philosopher developed the theory of legal rationalism?",
    "answer": "John Locke"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which philosopher influenced Baroque literature?",
    "answer": "Descartes"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which philosopher proposed the concept of natural reason?",
    "answer": "Baruch Spinoza"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which philosophical movement became the basis of empirical knowledge?",
    "answer": "Empiricism"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which philosophical movement influenced Baroque literature?",
    "answer": "Neoplatonism"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which philosophical work is written in defense of both feeling and reason?",
    "answer": "Treatise on Man"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which play by Goethe tells the story of Count Egmont?",
    "answer": "Egmont"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which play by Pedro Calderón de la Barca is considered the best in Spanish literature?",
    "answer": "Life is a Dream"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which play by Shaw is considered a reinterpretation of 'Pygmalion'?",
    "answer": "My Fair Lady"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which play did Shakespeare co-write that was published anonymously in 1623?",
    "answer": "Henry VIII"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which play did William Shakespeare write first?",
    "answer": "Titus Andronicus"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which play includes a scene with witches and trap rocks?",
    "answer": "Macbeth"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which play was written by Francesco Guarini?",
    "answer": "Fiammetta"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which play won the Pulitzer Prize for Drama in 2018?",
    "answer": "Cost of Living"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which poem by Ariosto includes elements of a chivalric romance?",
    "answer": "Orlando Furioso"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which poem by Francesco Petrarch became famous during the Renaissance?",
    "answer": "Africa"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which poem by Góngora is an example of literary Baroque?",
    "answer": "'Polidoro'"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which poem did Sidney write inspired by the Renaissance?",
    "answer": "Astrophil and Stella"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which poem did William Blake create as an illustrated manuscript?",
    "answer": "Songs of Innocence"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which poem did William Wordsworth conclude the poetic cycle 'Lyrical Ballads' with?",
    "answer": "Tintern Abbey"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which poem inspired John Milton to create 'Paradise Lost'?",
    "answer": "Jerusalem Delivered"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which poet described the construction of the Siena Cathedral in his poem?",
    "answer": "Orseto di Cetona"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which poet from Wolfsberg is considered the founder of German literature?",
    "answer": "Hartmann von Aue"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which poet introduced the genre of dialogue into literature?",
    "answer": "Petrarch"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which poet introduced the term 'platonic love' into literature?",
    "answer": "Petrarch"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which poet is known for his role in the 'Wars of the Roses'?",
    "answer": "John Lydgate"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which poet used baroque forms in their elegies?",
    "answer": "Martin Opitz"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which poet was known as 'the first sonneteer of France'?",
    "answer": "Malherbe"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which poet wrote 'An Essay on Criticism'?",
    "answer": "Alexander Pope"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which poet wrote 'The Battle of Colbie'?",
    "answer": "Walther von der Vogelweide"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which poet wrote the epic poem about El Cid Campeador?",
    "answer": "Anonymous"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which powerful order protects the Dragon Forest in 'Saga of the Ancient Worlds'?",
    "answer": "Order of Fire"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which principle of the Enlightenment era underlies utopian works?",
    "answer": "rationality"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which romantic was inspired by the Baroque?",
    "answer": "Calderon"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which series was awarded the Peabody Award in 2019?",
    "answer": "When They See Us"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which song is part of 'Carmina Burana'?",
    "answer": "O Fortuna"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which spell is forbidden to use in the Duels of the Lords of Cold?",
    "answer": "Wheel of Fortune"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which theme was particularly emphasized by Baroque drama?",
    "answer": "Vanitas"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which tragedy by Calderón combines elements of philosophy and religion?",
    "answer": "Life is a Dream"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which tragedy by Torquato Tasso is considered a model of Italian Renaissance tragedy?",
    "answer": "Aminta"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which trait is foreign to Baroque literature?",
    "answer": "Simplicity"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which treatise philosophically justifies the concept of civil authority?",
    "answer": "The Prince"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which value characterizes the kurtosis of a distribution?",
    "answer": "Kurtosis"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which work analyzes the political systems of the Enlightenment era?",
    "answer": "The Spirit of the Laws"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which work became a 'Barnes & Noble' bestseller in 2020?",
    "answer": "The Royal Hawk"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which work became an important source for studying the evolution of comic genres in ancient dramaturgy?",
    "answer": "The Asses"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which work became the basis of philosophy and social analysis in the 18th century?",
    "answer": "Emile"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which work belongs to Andreas Gryphius?",
    "answer": "The Tragedy of Cardenio"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which work by Aeschylus is known for its innovative stage effects?",
    "answer": "The Persians"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which work by Alberti significantly influenced architectural theory?",
    "answer": "Ten Books on Architecture"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which work by Béroul was written in Old French?",
    "answer": "The Romance of Tristan"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which work by Diderot criticizes religion and morality?",
    "answer": "The Nun"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which work by Edmund Spenser is associated with the Baroque period?",
    "answer": "The Faerie Queene"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which work by Emily Dickinson includes a philosophical exploration of death?",
    "answer": "Emily Dickinson's Poetry"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which work by Erasmus of Rotterdam became popular during his lifetime?",
    "answer": "In Praise of Folly"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which work by Francesco Petrarch demonstrates elements of classicism?",
    "answer": "Africa"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which work by Francesco Petrarch is written in the form of letters in Latin?",
    "answer": "Secretum"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which work by Francisco de Quevedo is an example of literary Baroque?",
    "answer": "Dream"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which work by François Villon showcased poetic technique and satire in medieval France?",
    "answer": "The Grand Testament"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which work by Geoffrey of Monmouth has a romantic title?",
    "answer": "The Life of Merlin"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which work by Henry James explores social boundaries and moral dilemmas?",
    "answer": "The Portrait of a Lady"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which work by Henry James explores the moral dilemmas of Americans in Europe?",
    "answer": "The American"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which work by Henry James explores the psychological aspects of women's lives through a ghost story?",
    "answer": "The Turn of the Screw"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which work by Henry James is considered the pinnacle of his later career and was published in 1904?",
    "answer": "The Wings of the Dove"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which work by Holbach is dedicated to atheism?",
    "answer": "The System of Nature"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which work by James Baldwin explores the themes of race, homosexuality, and religion in post-war America?",
    "answer": "Giovanni's Room"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which work by Jane Austen was published second in time?",
    "answer": "Pride and Prejudice"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which work by Jean de La Fontaine embodies classical ideals?",
    "answer": "'Fables'"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which work by John Cheever explores nostalgia and social decline?",
    "answer": "The Swimmer"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which work by John Cheever explores the theme of nostalgia and social decline through the character Neddy Merrill?",
    "answer": "The Swimmer"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which work by Juan Luis Vives became foundational for Renaissance pedagogy?",
    "answer": "The Education of Women"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which work by Juan de la Cueva contains elements of Baroque?",
    "answer": "Diana"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which work by Lamartine is based on the historical events of Greece?",
    "answer": "The Fall of Missolonghi"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which work by Leibniz develops the concept of monads?",
    "answer": "Monadology"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which work by Lope de Vega includes elements of Baroque?",
    "answer": "Fuente Ovejuna"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which work by Lucian satirizes the belief in gods?",
    "answer": "True History"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which work by Lucretius is dedicated to the philosophy of Epicurus?",
    "answer": "On the Nature of Things"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which work by Luis Vives was popular in Spain?",
    "answer": "The Fair of Saint Ottonel"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which work by Marilynne Robinson explores the theme of religion through a dying preacher's letter to his son?",
    "answer": "Gilead"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which work by Menander marked the beginning of New Attic Comedy?",
    "answer": "Dyskolos"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which work by Niccolò Machiavelli demonstrates elements of Renaissance drama?",
    "answer": "The Mandrake"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which work by Pico della Mirandola is considered central to his oeuvre?",
    "answer": "Oration on the Dignity of Man"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which work by Plautus is one of the earliest comedies?",
    "answer": "Amphitryon"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which work by Ralph Waldo Emerson, written in 1841, explores the philosophy of individualism and self-reliance?",
    "answer": "Self-Reliance"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which work by Sarah Orne Jewett explores female attachment and societal expectations in New England?",
    "answer": "The Country of the Pointed Firs"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which work by Sophocles is dedicated to the myth of Oedipus?",
    "answer": "Oedipus Rex"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which work by Thomas More contains utopian ideas?",
    "answer": "Utopia"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which work by Timothy Leary describes the psychological experience associated with the use of LSD?",
    "answer": "Trips"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which work by Voltaire parodies the Lisbon earthquake?",
    "answer": "Candide"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which work by Walt Whitman reflects the mystical connection between man and nature?",
    "answer": "Song of Myself"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which work by William Dean Howells explores the dreams and reality of Americans?",
    "answer": "A Hazard of New Fortunes"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which work by William Faulkner explores the decline of Southern aristocracy through the story of the Compson family?",
    "answer": "The Sound and the Fury"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which work by a Roman author, dedicated to agriculture, became a classic treatise on the subject?",
    "answer": "Georgics"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which work combines elements of magical realism and explores themes of memory and identity?",
    "answer": "The House on the Hill"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which work criticized morality and ethics?",
    "answer": "Candide"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which work criticized the concept of natural law?",
    "answer": "The Social Contract"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which work declared a fight against moralism and religious intolerance?",
    "answer": "Candide"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which work describes the connections of King Arthur with the Saxons and Picts?",
    "answer": "Historia Brittonum"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which work describes the legend of King Arthur as a historical figure?",
    "answer": "History of the Kings of Britain"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which work describes the pilgrimage of laypeople to Jerusalem in Old French?",
    "answer": "The Pilgrimage of Charlemagne"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which work did George Sand use to demonstrate her progressive views?",
    "answer": "Consuelo"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which work embodies American working culture through the metaphor of a naturalist man?",
    "answer": "John Henry"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which work explores the issue of government control over personal freedom?",
    "answer": "1984"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which work explores the issue of morality and social stigmatization through stories of death and burial?",
    "answer": "American Necropolis"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which work had a significant influence on periodical literature during the Enlightenment?",
    "answer": "Encyclopedia"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which work in 5 books was written by Likhnidsky?",
    "answer": "Anna of Persia"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which work in Latin discusses philosophical questions in the form of dialogues?",
    "answer": "De sapientia"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which work in epistolary form describes the drama of a solitary life in New England and an existential crisis?",
    "answer": "Letters to Melancholy"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which work in the form of letters delves into various aspects of love and passion of mythical heroes?",
    "answer": "Heroides"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which work includes descriptions of Byzantine monasteries and shrines?",
    "answer": "Byzantine Shrines"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which work initiated the utopian genre?",
    "answer": "Utopia"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which work initiated utopian ideas of the Renaissance?",
    "answer": "Utopia"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which work is a symbol of Baroque dramatic literature?",
    "answer": "Phantasmagoria"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which work is an example of a Baroque philosophical drama?",
    "answer": "Life is a Dream"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which work is considered foundational for the theory of knowledge?",
    "answer": "Critique of Pure Reason"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which work is considered the foundation of Renaissance poetry and contains elements of Platonic love?",
    "answer": "Canzoniere"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which work is dedicated to three generations of a family in New York and describes the transformations of the American Dream?",
    "answer": "The Golden Apple"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which work is often considered foundational in the psychological thriller genre and deals with themes of violence and redemption?",
    "answer": "Flashes of Darkness"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which work is the subject of philosophical reflections on justice and virtue?",
    "answer": "The Republic"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which work is written in prose form and covers themes of social inequality and metaphysics?",
    "answer": "The Tribes' Despair"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which work justified the establishment of civil rights?",
    "answer": "'The Social Contract'"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which work made Ludovico Ariosto famous as a Renaissance literature author?",
    "answer": "Orlando Furioso"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which work of English literature is a satire on utopian novels?",
    "answer": "Gulliver's Travels"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which work of French literature explores the life of a nobleman?",
    "answer": "Memoirs of a Nobleman"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which work of Leonardo da Vinci influenced Renaissance literature?",
    "answer": "Journals"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which work of the ancient Roman poet Horace is considered the watershed between old and new poetry?",
    "answer": "Odes"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which work received the Franz Kafka Prize in 2015?",
    "answer": "Ghost"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which work tells the story of a hero who sacrificed family happiness for the sake of revenge?",
    "answer": "Medea"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which work was created by a 13th-century poet in Old Icelandic?",
    "answer": "Ormsstinga saga"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which work was translated into Latin as 'Historia Calamitatum'?",
    "answer": "The Story of My Misfortunes"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which work was written by Alcuin of York?",
    "answer": "Dialogues"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which work was written by Longus?",
    "answer": "Daphnis and Chloe"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which work was written by Petrarch?",
    "answer": "Africa"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which work won the 'Goodreads Choice Award' in 2016?",
    "answer": "Morning Star"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which work, published in 1851, is based on real experiences of sea voyages and whaling?",
    "answer": "Moby Dick"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which writer formulated the aesthetic principles of classicism?",
    "answer": "Nicolas Boileau"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which writer is distinguished by baroque effusions in Spanish prose?",
    "answer": "Francisco de Quevedo"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which writer is known for his baroque-style sonnets?",
    "answer": "John Donne"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which writer wrote dialogues on philosophy and morality?",
    "answer": "Erasmus of Rotterdam"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who applied the methods of critical philosophy to religious beliefs?",
    "answer": "David Hume"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who compiled the 'Palatine Anthology'?",
    "answer": "Meleager"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who created the Barrier in 'The Wheel of Time'?",
    "answer": "al'Thor"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who created the Floating Castle spell on the Ancient Island?",
    "answer": "Gendalfus"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who created the concept of 'Paradise' and presented it in their epic?",
    "answer": "Milton"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who destroyed the Last Memorial in 'The Secret City'?",
    "answer": "Inquisitor"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who developed the philosophy of law based on utilitarianism?",
    "answer": "Bentham"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who founded the School of the Fighting Spirit in 'Legend of the Valkyrie'?",
    "answer": "Craig"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who has won the Pulitzer Prize twice?",
    "answer": "Colson Whitehead"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who holds the title 'Inquisitor' in Glen Cook's world?",
    "answer": "Inquisitor Senna"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who introduced the idea of 'general will' in Enlightenment literature?",
    "answer": "Rousseau"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who introduced the term 'platonic love' in Renaissance literature?",
    "answer": "Ficino"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who is considered Shakespeare's closest friend in the theatrical community?",
    "answer": "Richard Burbage"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who is considered the author of 'Historia Brittonum'?",
    "answer": "Nennius"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who is considered the author of the 12th-century chivalric epic about the cursed sword?",
    "answer": "Walter Map"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who is considered the author of the medieval chivalric romance 'The History of Troy'?",
    "answer": "Benoît de Sainte-Maure"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who is considered the author of the poem 'Insomnia'?",
    "answer": "Georg Büchner"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who is considered the founder of courtly poetry in Spain?",
    "answer": "Juan Ruiz"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who is considered the founder of the courtly poetry genre?",
    "answer": "Walther von der Vogelweide"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who is credited with the creation of 'Thebaid'?",
    "answer": "Statius"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who is known for theatrical shows?",
    "answer": "Jean-Paul Gaultier"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who is the author of \"Saga of Hakon\"?",
    "answer": "Snorri Sturluson"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who is the author of 'Patchwork Waltz'?",
    "answer": "Gaspara Stampa"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who is the author of 'The Book of the Three Beautiful and Virtuous Ladies'?",
    "answer": "Agnolo Firenzuola"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who is the author of 'The Pious Son', a work of Baroque poetry?",
    "answer": "Andreas Gryphius"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who is the author of 'The Tale of the Golden Fleece'?",
    "answer": "Lodovico Dolce"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who is the author of 'The Theory of Money and Credit'?",
    "answer": "Ludwig von Mises"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who is the author of 'Theatrical Manifesto', an important manifesto of classicism?",
    "answer": "Nicolas Boileau"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who is the author of the 18th-century French novel based on letters from aristocrats about love intrigues?",
    "answer": "Laclos"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who is the author of the allegory 'Russian Princes'?",
    "answer": "Foma Izansky"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who is the author of the book 'The Road to Nobel', which gained worldwide popularity?",
    "answer": "Michael Chabon"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who is the author of the book that won the Ignite Award in 2022?",
    "answer": "Archana Sarkar"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who is the author of the epic 'Thebaid'?",
    "answer": "Statius"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who is the author of the famous French tragedy about the conflict between a cardinal and a count?",
    "answer": "Corneille"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who is the author of the medieval romance 'Tristan and Isolde'?",
    "answer": "Thomas of Britain"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who is the author of the novel 'Ascanio'?",
    "answer": "Alexandre Dumas"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who is the author of the novel 'Countess of Montgomery'?",
    "answer": "Philip Sidney"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who is the author of the novel 'Her Fearful Symmetry', nominated for the Stockton Prize in 2007?",
    "answer": "Audrey Niffenegger"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who is the author of the novel 'Mirror and Sorrow', nominated for the National Book Award?",
    "answer": "Ellen Hilderbrand"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who is the author of the novel 'The Absentee', which is considered a pinnacle of Irish literature?",
    "answer": "Maria Edgeworth"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who is the author of the novel 'The Mill on the Floss'?",
    "answer": "George Eliot"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who is the author of the novel 'The Snake Hunt'?",
    "answer": "Lauren Groff"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who is the author of the novel 'Trust Exercise', which won the National Book Award in 2019?",
    "answer": "Susan Choi"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who is the author of the novel that won the 'International Dublin Literary Award' in 2020?",
    "answer": "John Wilson"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who is the author of the novel with elements of Greek romance and pastoral life, written during the Hellenistic period?",
    "answer": "Longus"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who is the author of the play 'As You Like It', which mentions the Forest of Arden?",
    "answer": "William Shakespeare"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who is the author of the poem 'Eldrid'?",
    "answer": "Alfred de Vigny"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who is the author of the treatise 'Oration on the Dignity of Man'?",
    "answer": "Pico della Mirandola"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who is the author of the work \"Books on the Family\"?",
    "answer": "Leon Battista Alberti"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who is the author of the work 'Liber Sancti Jacobi'?",
    "answer": "Aymeric Picaud"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who is the author of the work 'Lucretia' in the classicism style?",
    "answer": "Jean Rotrou"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who is the author of the work about the young Barbara?",
    "answer": "Goethe"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who is the author of the work describing the journey of a knight from the Arthurian cycle to the Holy Grail?",
    "answer": "Chrétien de Troyes"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who is the founder of the White Council in Tolkien's Middle-earth?",
    "answer": "Galadriel"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who is the head of House Arryn in 'A Song of Ice and Fire'?",
    "answer": "Jon Arryn"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who is the hero of the German epic poem about the battle of brothers?",
    "answer": "Hartmann von Aue"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who is the main character in Shakespeare's play about the rivalry of Roman generals?",
    "answer": "Antony"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who is the main character of George Eliot's novel 'Middlemarch'?",
    "answer": "Dorothea Brooke"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who kills Alina in 'The Wheel of Time'?",
    "answer": "Padan Fain"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who led the editorial team of the 'Encyclopedia'?",
    "answer": "Diderot"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who lived in the 12th century and wrote 'Roman de Renart'?",
    "answer": "Pierre de Saint-Cloud"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who possesses the power of the white dragons in the Wings of the Glacier?",
    "answer": "Rinaldo"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who published 'Ulysses' in 1922?",
    "answer": "Shakespeare and Company"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who received the Prague Literary Prize in 2018?",
    "answer": "Milan Kundera"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who translated 'Daphnis and Chloe' into Latin?",
    "answer": "Ausonius"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who translated Virgil into Italian during the Renaissance?",
    "answer": "Angelo Poliziano"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the author of the ancient Greek 'Geography'?",
    "answer": "Strabo"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the author of the work containing the famous scene of Clytemnestra's death?",
    "answer": "Aeschylus"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the main antagonist in Shakespeare's tragedy 'Othello'?",
    "answer": "Iago"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the prototype for Don Quixote in Cervantes' work?",
    "answer": "Alonso Quijano"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the publisher of the first posthumous publication of Jane Austen's works?",
    "answer": "Henry Austen"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who wrote 'Alexandria' (a work about the life of Alexander the Great)?",
    "answer": "Callisthenes"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who wrote 'Liber de coquina'?",
    "answer": "Pseudo-Apicius"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who wrote 'On the Defense and Glory of the French Language'?",
    "answer": "Jean du Bellay"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who wrote 'The Awakening'?",
    "answer": "Kate Chopin"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who wrote 'The Romance of the Fox'?",
    "answer": "Anonymous author"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who wrote 'The Shield of Achilles' in epic poetry?",
    "answer": "Homer"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who wrote 'The Twelve Idylls'?",
    "answer": "Theocritus"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who wrote 'The Year of the Golden Heat'?",
    "answer": "James Aldridge"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who wrote 'Thebaid'?",
    "answer": "Statius"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who wrote 'Weakness' and won the Liver Prize in 2018?",
    "answer": "Geneviève Bujo"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who wrote philosophical works in the Baroque style?",
    "answer": "Francisco de Quevedo"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who wrote the Anglo-Norman epic 'Roman de Brut'?",
    "answer": "Wace"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who wrote the bestselling novel 'Dangerous Dreams'?",
    "answer": "Ann Patchett"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who wrote the cycle of stories about the knight Tristan and Isolde?",
    "answer": "Gottfried von Strassburg"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who wrote the famous poem 'Madrigals'?",
    "answer": "Jacopo Sarti"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who wrote the novel 'The Bitter Father and the Merry Son' in the 18th century?",
    "answer": "Friedrich Schiller"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who wrote the novel 'Variations of Love and Agreement'?",
    "answer": "Jean-Paul Didierlaurent"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who wrote the novel nominated for the Stieg Larsson Prize?",
    "answer": "Camilla Grebe"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who wrote the novel that won the 'Cato' award in 2019?",
    "answer": "Maggie Nelson"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who wrote the novel that won the 'Golden Eagle' award in 2014?",
    "answer": "Anne Tyler"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who wrote the novel that won the Baileys Women's Prize for Fiction in 2016?",
    "answer": "Lisa McInerney"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who wrote the novel that won the Norwegian Brage Prize in 2010?",
    "answer": "Katarina Flatland"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who wrote the poem 'Pearl'?",
    "answer": "Unknown"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who wrote the poem 'Satires'?",
    "answer": "Horace"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who wrote the poem about Helen of Troy's return home?",
    "answer": "Guido delle Colonne"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who wrote the satire 'The Spark of Poetry'?",
    "answer": "Juvenal"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who wrote the three-volume work about Jeffers?",
    "answer": "Ludwig Tieck"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who wrote the work 'Sir Gawain and the Green Knight'?",
    "answer": "Anonymous"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who wrote the work that describes the rules of love magic?",
    "answer": "Ovid"
  },
  {
    "question": "Whose name is associated with the idea of 'the inverse relationship between science and freedom'?",
    "answer": "Jean-Jacques Rousseau"
  },
  {
    "question": "Whose work introduced the world to utopias?",
    "answer": "Thomas More"
  }
]